Guide to the American authors collection, 1832-1956
Department of Special Collections
- VAN PATTEN, NATHAN
  SEE CYRIL CLEMENS, FRANCIS MARION CRAWFORD, UNA JEFFERS, GLADYS A. LEWIS, VINCENT STARRETT, CARL VAN DOREN
- WAHRENBERG, OTTO (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - To David Starr Jordan, 14 Apr. 1928, ALS, 4pp.
    Source: David Starr Jordan (2 letters trans. to donor info. file)
  - The Bell at McBride, n.d., TMsS, 1p.
  - Hymn to the Ocean, n.d., TMs, 1p.
  - John McCann, n.d., TMs, 2pp.
  - The Old Hooker, n.d., TMs, 2pp.
  - Sea-power and overcoats, n.d., TMs, 2pp. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Song of the sea, n.d., TMs, 1p.
  - Testimony before the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries, 6 Mar. 1928, TMsS, 5pp.
  - A Voice from the foc'sl, n.d., TMs, 10pp.
  - The Voyage of Life, n.d., TMs, 15 pp.
  - The Wreck on the bar, n.d., TMs, 5pp.
- WALLING, ANNA STRUNSKY (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - In farewell A.S. 24 Nov. 1906 by George Sterling, TMs
  - Memories of Jack London, Dec. 1960, newsclipping
    Source: [Wallace Stegner]
- WARNER, CHARLES DUDLEY (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - To James Redpath, 8 May 1872, ALS, 1p.
- WATERSTON, REV. R.C.
  SEE WILLIAM CULLEN BRYANT
- WATSON, MARGARET
- WATSON, WILLIAM
- WEBSTER, GRACE MARGARET
  SEE JAMES WILLIAM BENNETT, BRISTOW ADAMS
- WEBSTER, MISS
  SEE MARY ROBERTS COOLIDGE
- WHITE, STEWART EDWARD (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - To William Owens, 17 Oct. 1933,w/env., TLS, 1p.
    Source: Mr. [William] Owens SEE ALSO CYRIL CLEMENS
- WHITMAN, WALT (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - To Sloan Kennedy, 28 May 1890, ALS, 1p.
  - Photograph, from Selected Poems, 1892
  - Walt Whitman in Camden by John Erskine, Jan. 1915, TMs, 4pp.
  - Walt Whitman's Politics from The American Mercury, Apr. 1929by Clifton Joseph Furness, TMs, 17pp.
  - Walt Whitman the Theme [ Herald], newsclipping
  - About Writers and Books The Chicago Evening Post 3 June 1899, newsclipping
  - Walt Whitman at Date by Horace L. Traubel, May 1891, magazine clipping, 18pp.
  - Red Paint on Whitman and other newsclippings, Boston Globe 22 Aug. 1938
  - Walt Whitman and Music New England Conservatory of Music, 15 Nov. 1937, photocopies, 1p.
  - To? photocopy letter with newsclipping from D. McKay publisher on sale of Leaves of Grass
  - Walt Whitman and Comstock on The Whirligig of Time, photocopy newsclipping by Benjamin Tucker, The New York Herald, Paris, 23 Nov. 1930
  - 5 facsimile cards (2-6) 1913
    Gift of Mrs. Helen Tufts Barlie
- WHITTIER, JOHN G. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - To Hannahill Darlington, 1 May 1889,w/env., ALs, 2pp.
    Source: K.F. Elkins 2 autographed cards
- WIGGINS, KATE DOUGLAS (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - 1 autographed card to Margaret Sloss
- WILLIS, NATHANIEL PARKER (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - To George I. Pumpelly 12 Apr. n.y., ALS, 2pp.
- WILBUR, RAY LYMAN
  SEE VAN WYCK BROOKS, PEARL S. BUCK, CYRIL CLEMENS, DOROTHY THOMPSON LEWIS, LINCOLN STEFFENS
- WILKINSON, ALFRED
  SEE RALPH WALDO EMERSON
- WILSON, HARRY LEON
  SEE GEORGE ADE
- WILSON, MR.
  SEE ALICE B. TOKLAS
- WINCHELL, EDWARD E.
- WINDUS, MR.
- WINTERS, WILLIAM (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - To Mrs. M.C. Sloss 20 June 1905, ALS, 3pp.
    SEE ALSO EDMUND C. STEDMAN
- WINTERS, YVOR (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The California Oaks poem n.d., TMsS, 1p.
  - Socrates - for Clayton Stafford poem, n.d., TMsS, 1p.
  - John Day, Frontiersman n.d., TMsS, 1p.
  - The Mesiac 1933, TMsS (initials) 1p.
  - To Hawthorne in Salem A Hundred Years Ago: From the San Francisco Peninsula n.d., TMsS, 1p.
  - A House n.d., TMsS, 1p.
  - An October Nocturne n.d., AMsS, 1p.
  - A Summer Commentary, TMsS
  - On the Portrait of a Scholar of the Italian Renaissance, TMsS, 1p.
  - Before Disaster, Poems by Yvor Winters, TMs 22pp.
    SEE ALSO ARVID SCHULENBERGER
- WOOD, CHARLES ERSKINE SCOTT (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - To Mr. and Mrs. John O'Shea from Sara Bard Field 15 Feb. 1930, ANS, 2pp.
  - To John O'Shea, 26 May 1934w/env., ALS, 2pp.
  - To John, 25 Aug. 1939, ALS, 2pp.
  - To Mr. and Mrs. John O'Shea, 12 Oct. 1939,w/env., ALS, 2pp.
  - To Mrs. John O'Shea, 15 Sept. 1941Sara Bard Field, TLS, 2pp.
  - To Mrs. John O'Shea, 16 Sept. 1941w/env., TLS, 2pp.
  - To John O'Shea, 23 Dec. 1941w/env., ALS, 2pp.
  - To Friends from Sara Bard Field (Wood) Christmas Card 1939
  - River Drift n.d., AMsS, 3 1/2pp.
  - Metaphysic n.d.on Emily Dickenson..., AMs, 1 1/2pp.
- WOODBURY
- YARD, ROBERT S.
- YEATS, WILLIAM BUTLER
- YOUNG, ELLA (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Vale Poem, To John O'Shea, 9 May 1955, AMsS, 1p.
  - Rasque Poem, To John O'Shea, 10 May 1955, AMsS, 1p.
  - To John O'Shea, 11 May 1955w/env., ALS, 2pp.